Bauchwitz, Kurt (Roy C. Bates); Papers ger011
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Manuscripts and Typescripts, 1928-1977; 3; 209 file folders
  - Prose Writings, 1940-1974; 3.2; 94 file folders
    - Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided into categories of classification on topics in biosophy (the art of living), dating from ca. 1948-1950; 3.2.52; typescript - ca. 2400 items (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 24-42)
      - S - Note slips on topics: self (I, person, subject, soul), sex, social order, synthesis, 364 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 38)
      - T - Note slips on topics: typology, training, 144 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 39)
      - V - Note slips on topics: values, 47 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 40)
      - W - Note slips on topics: work, writing, 82 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 41)
      - Mixed - Note slips on mixed categories, uncut, 17 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 42)
    - "Pebbles". Notes, diary entries, drafts of letters, thoughts on various topics, ca. 1950-1952; Undated; 3.2.53 (Box 14 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 1-4)
      According to the author: "These PEBBLES are rough copy, a daybook of original entry in which are recorded the fleeting accounts of my internal day, in their dis-order".
      - Hand - numbered leaves 1-180, 207p (Box 14 (3.2.53-"Pebbles". Notes, diary entries, drafts of letters), Folder 1)
      - Hand - numbered leaves 181-360, 228p (Box 14 (3.2.53-"Pebbles". Notes, diary entries, drafts of letters), Folder 2)
      - Hand - numbered leaves, 361-540, 211p (Box 14 (3.2.53-"Pebbles". Notes, diary entries, drafts of letters), Folder 3)
      - Hand - numbered leaves, 541-774, 268p (Box 14 (3.2.53-"Pebbles". Notes, diary entries, drafts of letters), Folder 4)
    - Notes, reflections, observations on various topics, 1955-1956; Undated; 261p (Box 14 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 5)
    - Notes, reflections, observations on various topics, ca. 1956-1957; Undated; 292p (Box 14 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 6)
    - "Question Marks". First series, Undated (ca. 1956-1958); 3.2.56 (Box 14 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 7-16)
      The author's "aphoristic diary", containing aphorisms, observations.
      - Notepads, 12 items 5" × 8" Digital Files (Box 14 (3.2.56-"Question Marks". First series), Folder 7-8)
        ca. 50 leaves ea., each page containing an observation or witty saying; these form the basis for Bates' first series of "Question Marks".
      - Pages 1-199, Typescript with few corrections. (Box 14 (3.2.56-"Question Marks". First series), Folder 9)
      - Pages 1-199, Carbon copies. (Box 14 (3.2.56-"Question Marks". First series), Folder 10)
      - Pages 200-399, Typescript with few corrections. (Box 14 (3.2.56-"Question Marks". First series), Folder 11)
      - Pages 200-399, Carbon copies. (Box 14 (3.2.56-"Question Marks". First series), Folder 12)
      - Pages 400-599, Typescript with few corrections. (Box 14 (3.2.56-"Question Marks". First series), Folder 13)
      - Pages 400-599, Carbon copies. (Box 14 (3.2.56-"Question Marks". First series), Folder 14)
      - Pages 600-746, Typescript with few corrections. (Box 14 (3.2.56-"Question Marks". First series), Folder 15)
      - Pages 600-746, Carbon copies. (Box 14 (3.2.56-"Question Marks". First series), Folder 16)
      - "Question Marks", 8-6-63 (Box 14 (3.2.56-"Question Marks". First series), Folder 17)
        Typescript with h. notes at the end. 2p. Also several cl. and note cards. 8 items.
    - "Question Marks". Series II, Undated (ca. 1962-1966); 3.2.57 (Box 15 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 1-10)
      2 copies. Original has h. corr., carbon copy has individual aphorisms numbered on each page.
      - Pages 1-200, Typescript with few corrections. (Box 15 (3.2.57-"Question Marks". Series II), Folder 1)
      - Pages 1-200, Carbon copies. (Box 15 (3.2.57-"Question Marks". Series II), Folder 2)
      - Pages 201-400, Typescript with few corrections. (Box 15 (3.2.57-"Question Marks". Series II), Folder 3)
      - Pages 201-400, Carbon copies. (Box 15 (3.2.57-"Question Marks". Series II), Folder 4)
      - Pages 401-600, Typescript with few corrections. (Box 15 (3.2.57-"Question Marks". Series II), Folder 5)
      - Pages 401-600, Carbon copies. (Box 15 (3.2.57-"Question Marks". Series II), Folder 6)
      - Pages 601-800, Typescript with few corrections. (Box 15 (3.2.57-"Question Marks". Series II), Folder 7)
      - Pages 601-800, Carbon copies. (Box 15 (3.2.57-"Question Marks". Series II), Folder 8)
      - Pages 801-1003, Typescript with few corrections. (Box 15 (3.2.57-"Question Marks". Series II), Folder 9)
      - Pages 801-1003, Carbon copies. (Box 15 (3.2.57-"Question Marks". Series II), Folder 10)
- Publications of Roy C. Bates, 1910-1973; 4; 21 file folders
  This series contains copies of most of the published writings of Kurt Bauchwitz/Roy C. Bates, either in the original or as photocopies; for a complete listing see "Bibliography of Published Writings.".
  - Multiple photocopies of poems, sketches, articles published in Der Jugend, 1910-1915; 20 items (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 11)
  - Photocopies of poems published in Nord und Süd, 1913 (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 12)
  - Der Lebendige. Ein Gedichtband in fünf Akten und einem Echo (Berlin: Liglio-Verlag), 1920; 2 copies (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 13)
  - Published reviews of Der Lebendige. 2 reviews, 1920 (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 14)
  - "Discovering the Sierra Nevada And What It Means to Reno and To Tourists Who Visit the West" [essay]Nevada State Journal (Reno, NV), 20 April 1941 (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 15)
    Multiple copies of original cl.
  - "The American Woman in Search of Time" [essay]Women's Welfare Journal (Madras, India), 1951 January (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 16)
    pp. 23-25. Offprint and pc. of article.
  - "Einsätze" [aphorisms]Neue Schweizer Rundschau, No. 3, 1953 July (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 17)
    pp. 173-174. Multiple photocopies of published aphorisms.
  - "Letters to the Editor"Boston Globe, 1961-1969 (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 18)
    Multiple photocopies of published letters.
  - "Letters to the Editor"New York Times, 1963; 1971 (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 19)
  - "Letters to the Editor"American Bar Association Journal, 1963-1972 (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 20)
    Multiple photocopies of published letters, magazine issues.
  - "Psychedelics and the Law: A Prelude in Question Marks" [essay], Psychedelic Review (Cambridge, MA), I, No. 4, pp. 379-392. 2 magazine issues containing article, 1964 (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 21)
  - "Copyright by Anon". [essay]American Bar Association Journal, LII, 1966 December (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 22)
    pp. 1140-1144. Pc.
  - "On Town Hall Issue" [Letter to the Editor]The Milton Record - Transcript (Milton, MA), 31 March 1967 (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 23)
    Pc.
  - "Question Marks" [aphorisms]The Middle Way. Journal of the Buddhist Society (London), Feb. 1968, p. 184; also Feb. 1969, p. 176, Undated (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 24)
  - "Form in Haiku (A Sequel)" [essay], Haiku Magazine (Toronto, Canada), II, No. 4 (1969); and "What Does a Haiku Mean?" [essay]Haiku Magazine (Toronto, Canada), III, No. 2 (1970), p. 38. Copies of magazine issues, 1969-1970 (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 25)
  - Wayne Wonderley and Roy C. Bates. "Rediscovering Kurt Bauchwitz: Der Lebendige" [essay]The University of Dayton Review, VI, No. 2, 1969 Fall (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 26)
    pp. 3-26. Offprint, 2 magazine issues.
  - "The Why of 'Judge Not'" [essay], PHP. A Forum for a Better World (Kyoto, Japan), 1970 October (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 27)
    pp. 22-23. 1 photocopy.
  - "Life is Monotonous" [sketch], PHP. A Forum for Better Living (Kyoto, Japan), p. 49, 1972 February (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 28)
    Multiple photocopies.
  - Counter / Measures. Magazine issue containing Bates' poems, 1973 (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 29)
  - "Two Poems"The Nantucket Review, No. 6, 38-19, 1976 June (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 30)
  - "Zwischenhändler" / "Go-between"Green River Review, VIII, No. 3, 218-219, 1977 (Box 15 (4-Publications of Roy C. Bates), Folder 31)
- Miscellaneous Materials, 1940-1977; 5; 73 file folders
  The miscellaneous materials files have been divided into two sections, those materials collected and used by Roy C. Bates, and those of his wife, Barbara Bent Bates.
  - Roy C. Bates Materials, 1939-1964; 5.1; 50 file folders
    The Roy C. Bates materials consist of materials pertaining to various organizations, legal topics, legal publications, hallucinogenic drug materials, etc. and include clippings, some notes, as well as published brochures and offprints.
    - Adoption. Notes, legal issues, clippings, etc. concerning adoption, Undated; ca. 20p (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 1)
    - American Association of D.M. Account Holders, Undated (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 2)
      Notes; 1 cl.
    - American Association of Former European Jurists, Undated; 3 items (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 3)
    - The American Law Book Company (Brooklyn 1, New York) - publications, Undated; 5.1.4 (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 4)
      - Corpus Juris Secundum. The Complete Encyclopedia of All the Law. "Conduct of Counsel", c. 1955
        Reprinted from Corpus Juris Secundum, Vol. LXXXVIII, pp. 304-403.
      - Legal Research by the use of Corpus Juris Secundum. By the Editorial Staff of the Publishers, ca. 1947; 60p
    - American Society of International Law, Undated; 5 items (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 5)
    - Arbitration. Brochures, pamphlets, Undated; 11 items (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 6)
    - Austro-American Association of Boston, Undated; 5 items (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 7)
    - Bar Review Course. Lecture Outlines. 4th ed. New York: Practicing Law Institute, 1954; 100p (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 8)
    - Buddhism, Undated; 6 items (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 9)
    - C.A.R.E., Undated (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 10)
      circa 10 items, incl. notes on packages sent to friends in Europe.
    - Carrington, Paul and William A. Sutherland. Articles of Partnership for Law Firms. American Bar Association Economics of Law Practice Series, Pamphlet Number Six. St. Paul, MN: West Publishing Co., [1962]; 102p (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 11)
    - Copyright law, Undated (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 12)
      Notes, materials. circa 15p.
    - The Corporation Trust Company (120 Broadway, New York 5), C T Corporation System publications, Undated; 5.1.13 (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 13)
      - When a Corporation is P.W.O.L., Undated; 15p
      - Some Contracts Have false Teeth, Undated; 13p
      - What Constitutes Doing Business. By a Corporation in States Foreign to the State of its Creation, 1956
    - Diet, Undated (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 14)
      circa 10p.; 1 cl.
    - Dream research, Undated (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 15)
      6 cl.
    - Ehegesetz, Undated; 1 reprint (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 16)
    - Famous Writers School, Undated; 3 items (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 17)
    - German Consul General, Undated (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 18)
      Notes, cl., newsletters.
    - Goethe House, Undated; ca. 60 items (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 19)
      Newsletters, announcements.
    - Halle (an der Saale), Germany (birthplace of Bates), Undated; 7 items (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 20)
    - Hallucinogenic drugs, Undated; 5.1.21 (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 21-23)
      - Clippings, miscellaneous, ca. 40 items (Box 16 (5.1.21-Hallucinogenic drugs), Folder 21)
      - Reprints (Box 16 (5.1.21-Hallucinogenic drugs), Folder 22)
        - "Apparent Results of Referrals of Alcoholics to LSD Therapy. (Interim Report)". Regina, Saskatchewan: Bureau on Alcoholism, Health and Welfare Building, December 31, 1962; 5p (Item 1)
        - Calder, J.F.A. "LSD Treatment of Alcoholics in a Mental Hospital (Memorandum), May 3, 1961 (Item 2)
          (from J.F.A. Calder to Dr. Humphry Osmond). 3p.
        - Chwelos, N., D.B. Blewett, C.M. Smith and A. Hoffer. "Use of D-Lysergic Acid Diethylamide in the Treatment of Alcoholism", Quarterly Journal of Studies on Alcohol (Yale Univ.), XX, No. 3, pp. 577-590, Sept. 1959 (Item 3)
        - Havens, Joseph. "A Memo to Quakers on the Consciousness-changing Drugs (LSD, Mescalin, Psilocybin)", J. Sci. Stud. Relig., III, No. 2. 14p, 1964 (Item 4)
        - Locke, Jeannine. "LSD. The Drug That Brings The Alcoholic Face to Face With Himself", The Star Weekly Magazine (Saskatoon), 16 February 1963; 3p (Item 5)
        - McGlothlin, William H. "Hallucinogenic Drugs: A Perspective with Special Reference to Peyote and Cannabis". (P-2937). The Rand Corporation, July 1964; 81p (Item 6)
        - O'Reilly, P.O., M.B., B.Ch., and Genevieve Reich. "Lysergic Acid and the Alcoholic", Diseases of the Nervous System, XXIII, No. 6, June 1962; 7p (Item 7)
        - Osmond, Humphry. "A Review of the Clinical Effects of Psychotomimetic Agents", Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, LXVI, No. 3, 14 March 1957 (Item 8)
          pp. 418-434.
        - "The Participation of Prisoners in Clinical Research. An Invitational Work Conference". Boston University, Law - Medicine Research Institute, February 12, 1962; 40p (Item 9)
        - Sherwood, J.N., M.D., M.J. Stolaroff, and W.W. Harman, Ph.D. "The Psychedelic Experience - A New Concept in Psychotherapy". 9, iv p. (Item 10)
        - Wasson, R. Gordon. "Notes on the Present Status of ololiuhqui and the other hallucinogens of Mexico", Botanical Museum Leaflets (Harvard Univ.), XX, No. 6, 22 November 1963 (Item 11)
          pp. 161-212.
        - Webster, Donald C. "New Role For An Ancient Drug", Globe Magazine (Toronto), 10 August 1963; 6p (Item 12)
      - Magazine issues, 8 items (Box 16 (5.1.21-Hallucinogenic drugs), Folder 23)
    - Harris, Arthur M. Letters to a Young Lawyer. St. Paul: West Publishing Company, 1950; 41p (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 24)
    - How to Use Shepard's Citations. Colorado Springs, CO: Shepard's Citations, Inc., 1951 (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 25)
      Also later printings: 1955, 1964; accompanied by Problems, Questions and Answers in the Use of Shepard's Citations.
    - Institute of Judicial Administration (40 Washington Square South, New York 12, N.Y.) publications, Undated; 5.1.24 (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 26-27)
      - You Litigate (2-U35), March 3, 1954 (Box 16 (5.1.24-Institute of Judicial Administration (40 Washingto), Folder 26)
        - Publication of Judicial Statistics (3-U65), June 24, 1955 (Item 1)
        - Administrative Boards for Automobile Tort Cases - Workmen's Compensation Compared (Delay and Congestion-Suggested Remedies Series, No. 8) (2-U63), May 15, 1956 (Item 2)
        - Compulsory Arbitration and Court Congestion. The Pennsylvania Compulsory Arbitration Statute (Delay and Congestion-Suggested Remedies Series No. 11) (4-U46), July 1, 1956 (Item 3)
      - Assignment Systems in Civil Cases, Continuances, and Judicial Vacations (Delay and Congestion-Suggested Remedies Series No. 9) (4-U18), August 1, 1956 (Box 16 (5.1.24-Institute of Judicial Administration (40 Washingto), Folder 27)
        - A Guide to Court Systems, November 1957 (Item 1)
        - Attitudes of the Bench and Bar Toward the Law's Delays. Paper presented at The National Conference on Congestion in the Courts. Department of Justice, Washington, C.C. (6-U70), June 16, 1958 (Item 2)
        - Rules of Court-Sources (6-U59), July 15, 1958 (Item 3)
        - Certification of Questions of Law (Delay and Congestion-Suggested Remedies Series, No. 13) (6-U49), August 1, 1958 (Item 4)
    - International Law Association, New York University Conference (1958). Conference materials concerning the uses of international rivers and lakes, Undated; 5.1.25; 14 items (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 28)
      Including:.
      - Principles of Law Governing the Uses of International Rivers and Lakes, April 1958
        Resolution Adopted by the Inter-American Bar Association at its Tenth Conference Held in November 1957, at Buenos Aires, Argentina, together with Papers Submitted to the Association. Washington, D.C.
      - Principles of Law and Recommendations on the Uses of International Rivers, May 1958
        Statement of Principles of Law and Recommendations with a Commentary and Supporting Authorities Submitted to the International Committee of the International Law Association by the committee on the Uses of Waters of International Rivers of the American Branch. Washington, D.C.
    - Japan, Undated; 5 items (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 29)
    - Lawyer's Co-operative Publishing Company (Rochester 14, New York) publications, Undated; 5.1.27 (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 30)
      - How to Use American Jurisprudence. c1938. 48p
      - How to Use American Law Reports. c1951. 48p
    - Legal topics, Undated; 12 items (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 31)
    - Literary topics, Undated; ca. 30 items (Box 16 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 32)
    - Maine - travel brochures, Undated; ca. 18 items (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 1)
    - Memberships. Miscellaneous membership information, Undated; ca. 10p (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 2)
    - Mental illness, schizophrenia. Notes, Undated; ca. 8 items (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 3)
    - Milton, Massachusetts. Notes; maps; town publications, Undated; 12 items (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 4)
    - National Council on Legal Clinics, Undated; 5 items (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 5)
    - Patents / Reichspatentamt. 3 texts, Undated (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 6)
    - Practicing Law Institute, Undated; 5 items (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 7)
    - The Prentice-Hall Corporation System (90 Broad Street, New York 4, N.Y.) publications, Undated; 5.1.37 (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 8)
      - Directors' Model Organizational Minutes and Stamp Taxes on Shares of Stock, Undated; 9, vii p
      - Corporate Facts and Fees. Featuring Comparative Corporation and Tax Law Charts, Undated
        vii, 8, ix p.
    - Quellen indischer Weisheit. Gedanken und Blumen. 1. Aufl. St. Gallen: Verlag Leobuchhandlung, c1962, Undated (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 9)
      With the word "PAPA" written on the cover in purple ink.
    - Radin, Max. The Law and You. New York: New American Library (A Mentor Book), 1948; 190p (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 10)
    - Rheinstrom, H. L'Influence du régime national-socialiste sur le droit privé allemand. Montreal: Valiquette, [1939]; 64p (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 11)
    - Society for Scientific Study of Religion, Undated; 5 items (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 12)
    - Synanon (Santa Monica, California), Undated; 2 items (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 13)
    - Travel, general, Undated; 6 items (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 14)
    - Wallace, George. 7 cl, Undated (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 15)
    - West's Law Finder. A Guide for Tomorrow's Lawyer, Undated; 2 issues (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 16)
    - World Peace Through Law, Undated; 8 items (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous cl., offprints, on various topics, Undated; ca. 40 items (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 18)
  - Barbara Bates Materials, 1948-1977; 5.2; 23 file folders
    The Barbara Bates materials can be divided into three main sections: materials pertaining to her own writings/ publications (5 folders); materials on subjects of interest (7 folders), primarily political topics, incl. her involvement in the 1956 campaign to elect Adlai Stevenson; and notes concerning the posthumous publication of the writings of Roy C. Bates (11 folders).
    - Writings of Barbara Bates, Undated; 5.2.1 (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 19-20)
      - Copies of magazine issues with articles by Barbara Bates (Box 17 (5.2.1-Writings of Barbara Bates), Folder 19)
        - "Attention, 81st Congress!", The Survey Midmonthly. Magazine of the Welfare Movement, LXXXIV, No. 12, December 1948 (Item 1)
          p. 368-369, 383-384. 2 copies.
        - "New York and Its Puerto Ricans", The Survey Midmonthly. Magazine of the Welfare Movement, LXXXV, No. 9, p. 487-488, September 1949 (Item 2)
      - "Yardstick for Freedom of Speech" (Box 17 (5.2.1-Writings of Barbara Bates), Folder 20)
        2c. Typescript and cc. 14p. ea.
    - Correspondence, Undated; 5.2.2 (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 21-23)
      - "Letters to the Editor", March 6, 1956; November 2, 1956 (Box 17 (5.2.2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
        And letters to public officials, incl.: Averell Harriman (September 23, 1956), Eleanor Roosevelt (November 3, 1956), Adlai Stevenson (March 22, 1956; April 8, 1956; October 2, 1956; October 9, 1956; November 9, 1956), Harry S. Truman (April 9, 1956).
      - "Letters to the Editor" and public officials. Drafts (Box 17 (5.2.2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
        Autograph 123p.
      - The Fund for the Republic (David F. Freeman). Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 17 (5.2.2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Collections of materials on various topics, Undated; 5.2.3 (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 24-30)
      - League of Women Voters, Milton, Massachusetts, 6 items (Box 17 (5.2.3-Collections of materials on various topics), Folder 24)
      - Literary topics. Notes (Box 17 (5.2.3-Collections of materials on various topics), Folder 25)
        Autograph ca. 40p.
      - Public Health Nursing, 1950; 4 issues (Box 17 (5.2.3-Collections of materials on various topics), Folder 26)
      - Publishers. Lists, notes on U.S. publishers, 5p (Box 17 (5.2.3-Collections of materials on various topics), Folder 27)
      - Religious topics (Box 17 (5.2.3-Collections of materials on various topics), Folder 28)
        Notes, cl.
      - Stevenson, Adlai, 1956 (Box 17 (5.2.3-Collections of materials on various topics), Folder 29)
        Campaign button and ribbon; 1 letter from the New York Committee for Stevenson, Kefauver and Wagner; form letter from Adlai Stevenson.
      - The Survey Midmonthly. Magazine of the Welfare Movement, 1947-1948; 7 issues (Box 17 (5.2.3-Collections of materials on various topics), Folder 30)
    - Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the writings of Roy C. Bates, Undated; 5.2.4 (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 31-41)
      - Alphabetical listing of poem titles, with notes concerning which titles were selected for projected volumes, some duplication (Box 17 (5.2.4-Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the), Folder 31)
        Autograph and cc. 20p.